In this town, it can all change… Like that.
Once Upon a Time... in Hollywood is a comedy, drama,
thriller film directed by Quentin Tarantino.
Los Angeles, 1969.
TV star Rick Dalton, a struggling actor specializing in westerns, and stuntman Cliff Booth,
his best friend, try to survive in a constantly changing movie industry.
Dalton is the neighbor of the young and promising actress and model Sharon Tate,
who has just married the prestigious Polish director Roman Polanski…
Rick Dalton, played by Leonardo DiCaprio.
Cliff Booth, played by Brad Pitt.
Sharon Tate, played by Margot Robbie.
Jay Sebring, played by Emile Hirsch.
'Pussycat', played by Margaret Qualley.
Jim Stacy, played by Timothy Olyphant.
Once Upon a Time...
in Hollywood is a 2019 period comedy-drama film
written and directed by Quentin Tarantino.
Produced by Columbia Pictures in association with Bona Film Group, Heyday Films, and Visiona Romantica, and distributed
by Sony Pictures Releasing, it is a co-production between the United States, United Kingdom, and China.
It features an ensemble cast led by Leonardo
DiCaprio, Brad Pitt, and Margot Robbie.
Set in 1969 Los Angeles, the film follows a fading actor and his adrenaline junkie stunt double as they
navigate the rapidly changing film industry with the threat of the Tate murders looming.
Announced in July 2017, it is Tarantino's first film not to involve Bob and Harvey Weinstein, as he ended his
partnership with the brothers following the sexual abuse allegations against Harvey Weinstein.
After a bidding war, the film was distributed by Sony Pictures Releasing,
which met Tarantino's demands, including final cut privilege.
Pitt, DiCaprio, Robbie, Zoë Bell, Kurt Russell and others
joined the cast between January and June 2018.
Principal photography lasted from June through November around Los Angeles.
Once Upon a Time in Hollywood is the final film to feature Luke Perry,
who died on March 4, 2019, and is dedicated to his memory.
Once Upon a Time in Hollywood premiered at the 2019 Cannes Film Festival on May 21, 2019, and was
theatrically released in the United States on July 26, and in the United Kingdom on August 14.
It grossed over $392 million worldwide and received acclaim from critics, although
historical inaccuracies and the portrayals of some artists were criticized.
The National Board of Review and the American Film Institute named Once Upon a Time in Hollywood as one of the
Top-10 films of 2019, and it won the Golden Globe Award for Best Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy.
Once Upon a Time in Hollywood was nominated for 10 awards at the 92nd Academy Awards, winning two (Best
Supporting Actor for Pitt and Best Production Design), and received numerous other accolades.
It has since been considered as one of the greatest
films of the 2010s and 21st century.
The Writers Guild of America ranked the film's screenplay
the 22nd-greatest of the 21st century.
Tarantino has stated that Once Upon a Time in Hollywood
is his favorite film that he has made.
A novelization, written by Tarantino in his debut as
an author, was published in 2021.
A sequel to the film, The Adventures of Cliff Booth, written by Tarantino and directed by David Fincher, with
Pitt in the lead role, is currently in production, and is scheduled to be released in 2026.
The film explores themes of movie business, male
friendship, cult, based on true story, celebrity.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and intense.